so what are the qualifications for a
那么，什么是一个资格
biblical counsellor in other words what
圣经辅导员换句话说是什么
qualities are essential for a man or a
品质对男人或男人来说至关重要
woman to be most effective in counseling
女人在咨询方面最有效
others from the Word of God that's our
来自上帝之道的其他人就是我们的
topic for the hour and the answer is
小时的主题和答案是
found in the Word of God in two key
在两个关键的上帝的话语中找到
passages there are 11 different passages
通道有11个不同的段落
in the New Testament where the word new
在新约圣经新词中
Sotelo is used and that's the word that
索特洛使用，这就是词
we get the idea of biblical counseling
我们得到了圣经辅导的想法
from one of those verses is Romans 15 14
其中一节经文是罗马书15 14
it says it this way I myself am
它这样说我自己就是这样
satisfied about you brothers that you
对你兄弟感到满意
are full of goodness filled with all
充满了善良的善良
knowledge and able to instruct one
知识并能够指导一个人
another that word instruct is the Greek
另一个词指示是希腊语
word new 3000 which can be also
新词3000可以是也
translated as admonish so romans 15 14
翻译为告诫所以罗马人15 14
tells us that goodness and knowledge are
告诉我们善良和知识
key in being able to counsel other
能够为其他人提供咨询的关键
believers Colossians 3:16 says this let
信徒歌罗西书3:16 说这让
the word of Christ dwell in you richly
基督的话丰富地住在你里面
teaching and admonishing one another in
教导和互相劝诫
all wisdom singing songs and hymns and
所有的智慧唱歌和赞美诗
spiritual songs with thankfulness in
感恩的精神歌曲
your hearts to God so the qualified
你的心对上帝如此合格
biblical counsellor must also have
圣经辅导员也必须有
wisdom
智慧
that's what Colossians 3:16 tells us and
这就是歌罗西书3:16告诉我们的
in that verse the word admonishing which
在那节经文中，劝戒哪个
is italicized there is the Greek new
斜体是希腊语的新词
tail so today we're going to examine
因此今天我们要去研究一下
each of these qualifications goodness
这些资格中的每一个都是善良的
knowledge and wisdom what does the word
知识和智慧这个词是什么
say about each one and how does that
说说每一个，怎么样
relate to our personal ministry in
涉及到我们个人的事工
discipleship and counseling after we
我们之后的门徒训练和辅导
look at each one I'm going to provide a
看看我要提供的每一个
little bit more
再多一点
to answer three questions what if I have
回答三个问题，如果我有的话
it what if I don't and how will this
如果我不这样做会怎样呢？
benefit my biblical counseling ministry
有益于我的圣经辅导部
and then at the end I'll also provide a
然后在最后我还会提供一个
brief survey of some other useful
其他一些有用的简要调查
resources that can also help contribute
资源，也可以帮助贡献
to your answering of that question of
你回答那个问题
the hour what are the qualifications of
小时的资格是什么
a biblical counsellor so all that's
一个圣经的顾问所以那就是
ahead well I must confess my outline
我必须承认我的大纲
today is not original this Romans 15 14
今天不是原来的罗马人15 14
and Colossians 3:16 model of goodness
和歌罗西书3:16善良的典范
kindness and wisdom was first presented
首先提出善意和智慧
and one of the books that began the
和其中一本书开始了
biblical counseling movement it was a
圣经咨询运动它是一个
book called competent to counsel it was
这本书被称为主管律师
published back in 1970 that's incredible
1970年出版，令人难以置信
when you think about that that's a lot
当你想到这一点 时，那就是很多
of years ago dr. Jay Adams in his book
年前博士。杰伊亚当斯在他的书中
confident to counsel used these passages
律师有信心使用这些段落
and these three things to describe what
和这三件事来描述一下
is necessary to counsel effectively from
有效地提供咨询是必要的
the word in fact one of Jay Adams
这个词实际上是杰伊亚当斯之一
favorite translations of the Bible was
最喜欢的圣经翻译是
the Williams translation and a phrase in
威廉姆斯的翻译和一个短语
Romans 1514 competent to counsel is the
罗马人1514有资格担任律师
one that he used as the title of that
一个是他作为的，标题
book well since then many biblical
从那以后很好地预订了许多圣经
counseling scholars have answered the
咨询学者已经回答了
same question what are the
同样的问题是什么
qualifications of a biblical counselor
圣经辅导员的资格
with these same truths from Romans 15 14
与罗马书15 14相同的真理
and Colossians 3:16
和歌罗西书3:16
perhaps none has been more clear and
也许没有人更清楚
practical than Paul trip in his great
实际比保罗在他的伟大之旅
book instruments in the Redeemers hands
在救赎者手中预订乐器
in this book doctor trip summarizes
在这本书医生之旅总结
these ideas of Romans 15 sessions 3:16
罗马人的这些想法15节3:16
in a four part diagram of biblical
在圣经的四部分图中
counseling that's well worth reading and
咨询非常值得一读
considering know and love know speak and
考虑知道和爱知道说话和
do
做
in that book in the four different
在那本书的四个不同
sections dr. Tripp explains clearly how
科博士。特里普清楚地解释了如何
goodness how knowledge and also how
善良知识如何以及如何
wisdom are you three of the scriptures
智慧是你三个经文
to other Souls well let's dig in the
对于其他灵魂，让我们深入挖掘
first qualification of a biblical
圣经的第一个资格
counsellor that we'll consider today is
我们今天会考虑的辅导员是
goodness our working definition for
善良我们的工作定义
goodness is this the habit pattern of
善良是这种习惯模式
doing good why this definition well the
做好为什么这个定义很好
Greek word translated goodness in Romans
希腊文翻译罗马人的善良
1514 literally means to do good it comes
1514字面上意味着要做好事
from the Greek word Agatha's which is
来自希腊语“ 阿加莎”的字样
translated good or kind in many New
在许多新的翻译好或好
Testament passages so goodness in Romans
遗嘱经文在罗马人中如此美好
15 14 refers to the habit pattern of
1514指的是习惯模式
doing good works in deeds this is really
在行动中做得很好，这是真的
essential for us in personal ministry
在个人事工中对我们至关重要
doing good works in deeds is a vital
在行动中做好事是至关重要的
part of our identity as redeemed people
我们作为被赎回的人 的身份的一部分
in Christ Ephesians 2:10 says that we as
在基督以弗所书2:10说我们是
Christians are created in Christ Jesus
基督徒是在基督耶稣里创造的
for good works there's that Greek word
好的作品就是那个希腊词
again which God prepared beforehand that
上帝预先准备的那个
we should walk in them also 2nd Timothy
我们也应该走进他们第二提摩太
3:16 and 17 landmark passage describes
3:16和17 标志性的段落描述
God's use of the god-breathed scriptures
上帝使用神圣经文
in the Christians life teaching reproof
在基督徒的生活教学责备
correction and training and
纠正和培训
righteousness
义
and what are the results of these
这些是什么结果
actions of God using the word in our
上帝使用我们这个词的行动
hearts that the man of God may be
上帝的人可能是的心
adequate equipped for every good work
每一项好工作都有足够的装备
there's that same word well my friends
我的朋友们也有同样的话
we are called to a life of good works as
我们被称为有益的生活
Christians God weaves into the
基督徒神织成
circumstances of each day the
每天的情况
opportunity
机会
to do good the Almighty God prepares
为全能的上帝做好准备
these appointments for us so that we can
这些约会对我们来说是可以的
honor him by doing these good things in
通过做这些好事来纪念他
many cases the doing good involves love
很多情况下，做好事涉及爱情
it involves kindness and it involves
它涉及善意，涉及到
service the Christian who is
为基督徒服务
characterized by goodness as it is used
以使用时的良好为特征
in Romans 1514 typically response to
在罗马书1514中通常会回应
God's pre-planned opportunities to do
上帝预先计划好的机会
good by actually doing good by doing
通过实际做好事来做好事
right by loving and by being kind and
向右爱和仁慈，
being glad to serve other people
很高兴为其他人服务
so the first qualification for the
所以对于第一个资格
biblical counselor is this commitment to
圣经辅导员这个承诺
do good when we're meeting with somebody
当我们与某人见面时，我们会做得很好
who's struggling with important issues
谁在努力解决重要问题
in life this this heart of love this
在生活中这是爱的心脏
purpose of doing good and of benefiting
做好事和受益的目的
this brother or sister in Christ is
这个在基督里的兄弟或姐妹是
really essential let's think about this
真的很重要让我们考虑一下
in a little more detail why is goodness
更详细一点，为什么是善良
so important in the relationships we
在我们的关系中如此重要
have in the biblical counseling room
有在圣经的咨询室
there are at least two reasons one of
其中至少有两个原因
them is John 13:34 and 35 as a biblical
他们是约翰福音13:34和35作为圣经
counselor you represent Jesus Christ as
辅导员，你代表耶稣基督
his disciple if somebody's coming to you
他的门徒，如果有人来找你
to find out what does the Bible say
找出圣经所说的话
about what's going on in my life they're
大约在我的生活发生了什么事情 他们是
gonna regard you as a disciple of Christ
要把你视为基督的门徒
you want to be that disciple of Christ
你想成为基督的门徒
and in John 13:34 and 35 Jesus tells us
耶稣在约翰福音13:34和35中告诉我们
what it what it means to be that
这是什么意思
disciple he said a new commandment I
弟子他说了一条新诫命
give you that you love one another just
给你，你只是爱彼此
as I have loved you you also
因为我也爱你，你
love one another by this all people will
所有人都愿意彼此相爱
know that you are my disciples if you
如果你知道你是我的门徒
have love for one another so in the
有彼此在热恋中的
biblical counseling room you may be
你可能是圣经咨询室
meeting with a sinning Christian you may
你可能会遇到犯罪的基督徒
be meeting with a weak Christian who
与一个弱小的基督徒会面
needs to understand God's promises and
需要了解上帝的承诺和
how they relate to his or her life or an
它们与生活或生活的关系
image for a Christian who just really
一个真正的基督徒的形象
doesn't understand much about the word
对这个词不太了解
and needs to understand the word to be
并且需要理解这个词
able to follow God better well in each
能够更好地跟随上帝
of these cases it's imperative that your
在这些情况下，你的当务之急是必不可少的
counsel II recognizes you as a disciple
律师II承认你是门徒
of Jesus Christ if they do they will
耶稣基督如果他们愿意的话
hear God's Word from you more readily
从你听到神的话语 更容易
well how can you accomplish that goal of
那你怎么能实现这个目标呢？
being regarded as a disciple of Christ
被视为基督的门徒
loved like he loves you that's what
喜欢他爱你就是这样
Jesus is telling us in John 13:34 and 35
耶稣在约翰福音13:34和35中告诉我们
Christian counselor this means you
基督徒辅导员这意味着你
genuinely love and care each person for
真正爱和关心每个人
each person that God brings across your
上帝带给你的每个人
path you regard it as a privilege to
路径你认为它是一种特权
serve them to walk with them down the
为他们服务，与他们一起走下去
road of the difficult times in their
在他们的困难时期的道路
life to be able to care for them and
生活能够照顾他们和
communicate the word to them sometimes
有时候会把这个词告诉他们
that love involves service beyond the
爱情涉及到超越的服务
meetings that you have with them in the
你和他们在一起的会议
counseling room this love that Christ
辅导室这爱基督
had for us involved him laying down his
有我们参与他放下他
life for us and so our mission is to lay
生活对我们，因此我们的 任务就是打好
down our lives for the counsel ease God
为了安慰上帝而放弃我们的生活
brings us I would summarize it this way
带给我们我会这样总结一下
probably 75 percent of counseling cases
可能有75％的咨询案例
that I've been involved with over the
我曾经参与其中
years require goodness in the forms of
岁月需要良好的形式
true concern christ-like love for the
真正关心基督般的爱情
counsel a good preparation prayer and
建议做好准备祷告
personal communication of care in the
个人护理沟通
counseling room this Christian love is
咨询室这个基督徒的爱是
necessary for effectiveness etic counsel
有效性的必要性etic律师
according to romans 15 14 and I'd say
根据罗马书15 14，我会说
the other 25% of the cases require
其他25％ 的案件需要
goodness to an even greater degree as an
作为一个更好的程度的善良
example consider this case there was a
例子考虑这种情况有一个
man that I met with every Tuesday night
我每周二晚上遇到的男人
for a few months during that time I
对于那个时候我 在几个月
prayed I visited visited him at his home
我拜访了他在家中拜访过他
I took phone calls from him after he had
我拿着电话从他得了之后
had distressing conflicts with his wife
与妻子发生了令人痛苦的冲突
I spoke to her both by phone and in
我通过电话和通话告诉了她
person with him we took many walks
跟他在一起的人我们走了很多路
together and talked about the word and
一起谈论这个词和
life there were many times when he
生活中有很多次他
needed to be exhorted from God's Word
需要从上帝的话语中劝诫
and there were other times when he
还有其他时候他
needed to be comforted with the promises
需要得到承诺的安慰
of God's Word to know that they were
神的话语知道他们是
true there were many times during those
确实有很多次
14 weeks that I looked this guy in the
14周，我看着这个家伙
eye and I said I love you brother and
眼睛和我说我爱你兄弟
that was true and he believed that I
这是真的， 他相信我
think that dynamic of christ-like love
认为充满了基督般的爱情
was an important part of this ministry
是这个事工的重要组成部分
to this man
对这个男人
during what he would describe as the
在他所描述的期间
most difficult season in his life of
他生命中最困难的季节
course in the end it was God who changed
当然最终是上帝改变了
his heart through the word it was God
他的心通过这个词就是上帝
who brought his wife to salvation and it
谁带他的妻子去救赎呢
is God who continues to work in this
是继续在此工作的上帝
couple's life who've are doing great in
夫妻俩的生活在做得很好
their walk with God these days but I
这些天他们与上帝同行，但我
think that if my friend was here I think
想想如果我的朋友在这里，我想
if you asked him today
如果你今天问他
he would tell you that he regarded my
他会告诉你他认为我的
counsel from God's Word as from a
来自上帝之道的劝告
disciple of Christ because he saw the
基督的门徒，因为他看到了
love that I had for him and also he saw
我爱他，也看到了
the love that I have for my wife in our
我有我的妻子的爱情我们
relationship so represent Jesus Christ
关系所以代表耶稣基督
as his disciple strive to love as Christ
因为他的门徒努力像基督一样爱
loved lay down your life well why is
喜欢放下你的生活，为什么
goodness so important in biblical
善良在圣经中如此重要
counseling relationships number two we
咨询关系我们二号
must love Paul loved the Philippians he
必须爱保罗爱他的腓立比人
told them so in verse 8 of chapter 1 of
在第1章第8节告诉他们
his letter he said God is my witness how
他在信中说，上帝为我作证如何
I yearned for you all with the affection
我怀着感情向往你
of Christ Jesus he also loved Christians
基督耶稣，他也爱基督徒
that were in churches that weren't so
那些在教会中并非如此
strong in the Corinthian church he said
他说，在哥林多教堂里很坚强
in second Corinthians 4:5 for what we
在哥林多后书4：5中为我们所做的事
proclaim is not ourselves but Christ
宣告不是我们自己， 而是基督
Jesus as Lord with ourselves as your
耶稣是我们自己的主
servants for Jesus sake he told them
为了耶稣的缘故，他告诉他们
literally that he was their slave for
从字面上看，他是他们的奴隶
the sake of Jesus Christ and that was a
耶稣基督的缘故，那是一个
difficult church would you or I make
你或我会做出困难的教会
that commitment to a church with as many
对多个教会的承诺
problems as the church at Corinth we
作为哥林多教会的问题我们
would if we have the goodness that
如果我们有善良的话会的
results in christ-like love Paul talks
导致基督般的爱保罗谈话
about this love for the Corinthians also
关于对哥林多人的这种爱也
in second Corinthians 12:15
在哥林多后书12:15
he says I will most gladly spend and be
他说我很乐意和他一起度过
expended for your souls
为你的灵魂消耗
wait may each of us be committed at this
我们每个人都可以在此等待
level to the people that God brings to
对上帝所带来的人的 水平
us for discipleship or counseling
我们的门徒训练或辅导
whether they more resemble the Philippi
他们是否更像腓立比
and they're doing well and their
而且他们做得很好，他们的
response to the word is immediate and
对这个词的回应是立竿见影的
positive or whether they're more like
积极或是否更像
the church at Corinth where it's a long
在科林斯的教堂那里很长
process in a difficult one well what if
在困难的过程中如何处理
you already have it
你已经拥有它了
well when I say this you understand that
好吧，当我这样说你明白了
I don't think any of us are perfect in
我认为我们中的任何人都不是完美的
christ-like love but I'm using the
基督般的爱，但我正在使用
phrases in this message what if you
这条短信中的短语如果你
already have it and what if you don't
已经拥有它，如果你不这样做
just to say hey if this is one of the
只是说嘿，如果这是其中之一
areas of your life that it seems like
你的生活领域，它似乎像
you're particularly strong or if it's an
你特别强壮，或者它是一个
area where you realize wait I need some
你意识到等待的地方我需要一些
work here that's what these phrases are
在这里工作，这就是这些短语
meant to convey so what if you what if
意思是传达如果你如果如果
you already have it what if one of the
你已经拥有它，如果其中之一
strengths of your walk with God and your
你与上帝和你的 同行的优点
ministry to others is this christ-like
对他人的事工是这样的基督
love communicate your love for your
爱表达你对你的爱
counsel ease and others for the purpose
为此目的提供便利和其他人的建议
of identifying yourself as a disciple of
认定自己是一个门徒
Christ people need to know that you care
基督徒需要知道你在乎
about them with this christ-like love
关于他们这种基督般的爱
love your counsel leaves with true
爱你的忠告离开真实
christ-like love consider it a privilege
基督般的爱认为这是一种特权
and an honor to seek to emulate Jesus
并且很荣幸能够效法耶稣
Christ by laying down your life for
基督借着放下你的生活
these people that God has brought across
这些人，上帝已经把对面
your path rely on God's grace and His
你的道路依靠上帝的恩典和他的
Word to love selflessly regardless of
无论如何，无私地爱的话语
the counsel ease responds to you or to
律师轻松回应你或
the word don't take it personally you're
这个词不要以个人为主
there to serve not to be loved or
在那里服务不被爱或
appreciated also enjoy the interaction
赞赏也享受互动
between you and your God as you honor
当你尊重你和你的上帝之间
him with care compassion and involvement
他谨慎同情和参与
in the lives of your counsel ease this
在你的律师的生活中缓解这一点
is one of the great adventures that goes
是一次伟大的冒险之旅
on between the counselor or just the
在辅导员之间或只是
decipher and the Lord we need his help
破译和主我们需要他的帮助
to love like that and we're seeking to
爱这样的，我们正在寻求
represent him well by loving the way
代表他深受爱的方式
we've received love from him
我们收到了他的爱
and so the interaction that goes on
所以正在进行的互动
between you and the Lord is a great
你和主之间是伟大的
adventure as you strive to put into
你努力投入的冒险
practice christ-like love in each
在每个人中练习基督般的爱
relationship be strong in love well what
恋爱中的关系很好
if you don't what if you have to work
如果你不这样做，如果你必须工作
really hard at being selfless and
真的很难无私
noticing the needs of others or at
注意到他人或他人的需要
expressing christ-like love in words or
用语言表达基督般的爱
deeds what if the truth of it is you
如果事实真相，你会怎么做？
really don't normally think in terms of
真的通常不会想到
putting other people first what if you
如果你把别人放在首位
find it difficult to care I mean can't
发现很难照顾我的意思是不能
that other person just be a little less
那个人只是少一点
needy well the word says this number one
这个词就是这个号码
know that you must love first John 3:16
知道你必须先爱约翰福音3:16
we know love by this that he laid down
我们知道他的爱是他放下的
his life for us and we ought to lay down
他的 一生为我们和我们应该躺下
our lives for the brothers
我们为兄弟们的生活
we must love and first John 4:11 says it
我们必须爱， 并且首先约翰福音4:11说
a different way beloved II of God so
一个不同的方式， 亲爱的上帝二世所以
loved us we ought to love others so we
爱我们， 我们应该爱别人，所以我们
need to love we must strive to love
需要爱我们必须努力去爱
number two if this isn't an area of
如果不是这个区域，则排名第二
strength for you study God's love and
你有力量研究上帝的爱和
study the love of Jesus Christ in the
研究耶稣基督的爱
scriptures we love because He first
我们喜欢的经文，因为他先
loved us
爱我们
spend a lot of time considering how he
花很多时间考虑他如何
loved us you know be a lot easier to
爱你我们你知道要容易多了
emulate that appreciate and give thanks
仿效欣赏并表示感谢
daily for God's love and for the love of
每日神的爱和爱
Jesus Christ that's a that's a great
耶稣基督，这是一个伟大的
thing to do anyway but doing so helps us
无论如何 要做的事情，但这样做有助于我们
think in terms of love understand love
从爱的角度思考，了解爱情
and communicate the proper response to
和通信，以适当的反应
love to the Lord well how will this
我很爱这位主
benefit our biblical counseling ministry
使我们的圣经辅导部受益
if we are strong in this goodness if we
如果我们的强项是这个善良，如果我们
are strong in christ-like love the
在基督般的爱中坚强
biblical counselor who is effective in
有效的圣经辅导员
this love who practices this goodness in
这种爱实践了这种善良
their relationships with people that
他们与人的关系是
their disciple in our counseling will be
他们的弟子将在我们的辅导中
trusted more they'll also be heard more
信任更多他们也会被更多地听到
clearly at those points where you must
显然在你必须的那些点上
confront sin and ultimately and most
面对罪恶，最终和最重要的
importantly will better honor God so
重要的是会更好地尊重上帝
goodness one of the qualifications of a
善良的资格之一
biblical counsellor the second
圣经辅导员第二
qualification for the biblical
圣经的资格
counsellor is knowledge Romans 15 14
辅导员是知识罗马书15 14
where when Paul says that he is
当保罗说他是的时候
satisfied that these brothers are able
这些兄弟能够满意
to instruct one another the second
互相指导第二个
reason is they're filled with knowledge
原因是他们充满了知识
the root word translated knowledge is
翻译知识的根词是
used over 275 times in the new
在新的使用超过275次
testament the what are the main things
遗嘱主要的东西是什么
that somebody with this knowledge needs
有这种知识需要的人
to know according to the New Testament
根据新约圣经 知道
we are told to know truth we are told to
我们被告知知道我们被告知的真相
know God and we are told to know the Son
认识上帝，我们被告知了解儿子
of God in John 17:17 jesus said your
在约翰福音17:17 耶稣说你的
word is truth
这个词就是真理
when he prayed to God the Father so we
当他向我们的父神祈祷时
are to know truth we know truth by
要知道真相我们知道真相
knowing God's Word this is the first of
知道上帝的话这是第一个
the three things we are to know know the
我们要知道 的三件事情都知道
word no the word by studying and
通过学习和改变这个词
applying it in your own life each day
每天在自己的生活中应用它
we've talked about Hebrews 4:12 and 13 a
我们已经谈过希伯来书4:12和13a
few times during our fall conference
我们秋季会议期间几次
this dynamic is so important it says
它说，这种动态非常重要
this for the word of God is living and
这对神的道是活
active and sharper than any two-edged
比任何双刃更活跃，更敏锐
sword piercing to the division of soul
剑刺穿灵魂的分裂
and spirit of joints and marrow and
和精神的关节和骨髓和
discerning the thoughts and intentions
辨别思想和意图
of the heart and no creature is hidden
心脏，没有生物被隐藏
from his sight but all things are naked
从他的视线， 但所有事情都是赤裸裸的
and exposed to the eyes of him to whom
并暴露在他的眼中
we must give account so this this
我们必须考虑到这一点
passage describes in detail this deep
篇章详细描述了这一点
level of personal interaction that can
可以的个人互动水平
go on between us and the Almighty
继续我们与全能之间
Creator God every day as we spend our
造物主的每一天，我们花
time in the word God Himself is
上帝自己这个词的时间
communicating to us at the deity at the
在神的神灵沟通
deepest level of our soul through his
通过他的最深层次的灵魂
word as we study it apply it and respond
在我们研究它的时候应用它并做出回应
to it each day God's the only one who
每天上帝是唯一的一个人
understands the thoughts and intentions
理解思想和意图
of our heart we may understand some of
在心里，我们可能会理解一些
them he knows all of them and he's
他们知道他们所有人，而且他是
willing to interact with us at that
愿意与我们互动
level God makes it his occupation to
神级使得他的占领
keep track of our desires and motives
跟踪我们的欲望和动机
2nd chronicles 16:9
第二次记载16：9
tells us that God searches the heart of
告诉我们，上帝寻找的核心
all seven billion people that there are
所有七个十亿人有
on earth right now and what's he looking
现在在地球上，他在寻找什么
for he's looking for the hearts that are
因为他正在寻找那些心灵
completely his proverbs 17 3 says
完全是他的谚语17 3说
something similar the Lord who tests
类似于测试的主
hearts what does he find in your heart
他心中发现了什么
in my heart when he tests us he chooses
当他选择测试我们时，在我的心里
to disclose some of that information
披露一些信息
through his word after he does that when
通过他的话，他不会当 后
he exposes the good and the bad at the
他暴露了好的和坏的
core of our beings he then offers us
我们的核心是他然后提供给我们的
what we really need in those times mercy
在那些时代我们真正需要的是什么怜悯
and grace as we repent of the sins that
当我们忏悔那些罪恶时，我们就会恩惠
he's exposed he offers that mercy of
他暴露了他提供的怜悯
restoration and as we seek to change as
恢复和为我们寻求改变的
we seek to replace those sins with
我们试图用这些罪来取代这些罪
righteousness he says that we should
正义他说我们应该
come to him with confidence as we
我们有信心地来找他
request we as we request the grace to
请求我们，我们要求恩惠
help in time of need so he will give us
在需要的时候提供帮助，这样他就会给我们
that help that we need to change in
这有助于我们需要改变
response to the word this is so
回应是这样的话
important we need to know the truth and
重要的是我们需要知道真相和
we need to respond to it that honors God
我们需要回应尊重上帝的事
and the more we excel at that dynamic
我们越是擅长这种动态
that interaction with the Lord then the
然后与主的互动
more effective will be in leading
更有效的将领先
disciples and counsel ease through that
门徒和律师通过这种方式轻松自如
same process secondly we can know the
同样的过程其次我们可以知道
Scriptures by reading daily a pretty
每天阅读一本漂亮的经文
simple thing but an important thing turn
简单的事情，但重要的事情转向
over to page 188 in your syllabus here's
在你的教学大纲中的第188页
one possible format for such a thing you
对于这样的事情一个可能的格式，你
find a page like this
找到这样 一个页面
it's a simple bible study method it's
它是一种简单的圣经学习方法
based on James 1:25 James 1:25 tells us
基于雅各书1:25 雅各书1:25告诉我们
that we should be doers of the word
我们应该坚持这个词
that's what God is looking for is people
这就是上帝所寻求的是人
who not just hear the word but do it so
谁不只是听到这个词而是这样做
each one of these pages goes along with
这些页面中的每一页都伴随着
the chapter in the New Testament and so
新约中的章节等等
as you read through the chapter you'd
当你读完这一章的时候
write down what are the main ideas of
写下什么是主思路
this chapter in the first section and
本章的第一节和
then the next part is what are the key
然后下一部分是关键
verses what are the what are the verses
经文是什么什么是诗
that apply most to my life today they
这对我今天的生活最重要
may be verses where God is encouraging
可能是上帝鼓励的经文
you hey buddy you're living this already
你嘿伙计你已经生活了
keep up the good work or they might be
保持良好的工作或他们可能
verses where he's exposing the thoughts
他揭露思想的经文
and intentions of the heart that aren't
心灵的意图并非如此
right hey here's something you need to
嘿，这是你需要的东西
change brother so we write down those
改变兄弟所以我们写下那些
key verses and then we consider what do
关键经文，然后我们考虑做什么
I need to do to be a doer of the word
我需要做的是做一个人的话
because that's that's what God is
因为那是上帝的意思
looking for people who do the word so if
寻找那些如果这样做的人
these are the things that it says and
这些是它说的和
these are the ideas what do I actually
这些是我实际上的想法
need to want and think and do for my
需要为我的想法，思考和做
life to be equal to what those
生命等于那些
scriptures are saying and then at the
经文说，然后在
end we're gonna pray if God has exposed
如果上帝暴露了， 我们会祈祷
any sin we're gonna confess that sin and
任何罪，我们要承认罪和罪
repent of it and then we're also going
悔改然后我们也要去
to pray for God's help to obey his word
祈求上帝帮助他顺服他的话
when when sky and aleeza my son and
当天空和aleeza我的儿子和
daughter were in junior high in high
女儿在初中高中
school the two of them along with my
学校他们俩连同我的
wife Julie and I went through the New
妻子朱莉和我经历了新的
Testament with this format we we do one
用这种格式的遗嘱，我们做一个
chapter each time we do that two or
章节每次我们做那两个或
three times a week we all spent our own
一周三次我们都花了我们自己的
time in the word other days but on those
时间在单词的其他天，但这些
days we spent that time together what
天，我们花了当时一起什么
happened was we would each interact with
发生的事情是我们每个人都会互动
God we'd read the chapter out loud and
上帝，我们读到的章节大声和
then we'd all do all the writing on our
然后我们都会写下我们的所有文章
own and then afterward we talked about
自己然后我们谈到了
it what went on between you and the Lord
你和主之间发生了什么
during this time
在这段时间里
well Julie and I made it our policy to
朱莉和我做了我们的政策
share everything well except for one if
分享一切， 除了一个如果
the application had something to do with
该应用程序与此有关
the intimate part of our relationship we
我们的关系，我们的隐秘部位
wouldn't we wouldn't share that with the
难道我们不会与之分享
junior higher kids so but anything else
初中级孩子，但其他任何东西
that we would just tell them yeah here's
我们只是告诉他们是的
what went on between us and the Lord and
什么我们和神之间 继续
so as the four of us engaged in this
所以我们四个人都参与其中
activity of interacting with God and God
与上帝和上帝互动的活动
causing the word to be living and active
使这个词生活和活跃
in us striving to become doers of the
在我们努力成为实干家
word some great things happened I mean
我的意思是发生了一些伟大的事情
we were all transparent we understood
我们都明白透明了
each other way more and we understood
彼此的方式更多，我们理解
the inner workings and the interaction
内部运作和互动
between each of us and God during that
在那期间我们每个人和上帝之间
time our identity became for Christians
我们的身份成为基督徒的时间
who were seeking to become more like
谁想要变得更像
Christ and for Christians who were
基督和曾经的基督徒
praying for each other and encouraging
为彼此祈祷并鼓励
each other and keeping each other
彼此相互保持
accountable with that same goal we were
对我们的目标负责
still parents and children we still had
还是家长和孩子，我们仍然有
those roles within the family but as as
家庭中的那些角色，但同样如此
Christians as people and within those
基督徒人与那些内
roles that's what our identity became
角色就是我们的身份
that's what we were doing together I
这就是我们正在做我在一起
think it was really valuable on so many
认为这对很多人来说真的很有价值
levels because of course God did what he
因为当然，上帝的水平做了他
does through the word he caused each of
通过他造成的每一个字
us to change and grow but we each had a
我们改变和成长，但我们每个人都有一个
part in that and that was great and
参与其中，这很棒
because because God would reveal things
因为上帝会揭示事物
in from the depths of each of our hearts
从我们每个人的心灵深处
through the word and we'd interact with
通过这个词，我们将与之互动
the Lord and we talk about those it gave
主，我们谈论它给的那些
us a great opportunity to understand how
我们是一个理解如何的好机会
we could best love care lead serve and
我们可以最好地爱护理铅服务
help each other so it's important for
相互帮助， 因此这很重要
each of us to interact with the word at
我们每个人都 在用这个词来互动
that kind of level on a daily basis and
这种水平每天和
there's a great opportunity for us in
对我们来说是一个很好的机会
our ministries of all kinds within our
我们的各个部门
families and other discipleship
家庭和其他门徒训练
ministries to have
各部委都有
the word being studied and discussed at
正在研究和讨论的词
this level well there's a third way that
这个水平还有第三种方式
we can know God's word better the first
我们可以更好地了解上帝的话语
thing we're supposed to know is the word
我们应该知道的是这个词
and that's through Advanced Studies
这是通过高级研究
there's a list of systematic theologies
有一系列系统神学
over on page 191 89 excuse me and we'll
请原谅，请原谅我，我们会
talk about those in a few minutes in a
在几分钟内谈论那些
little more detail but that's another
更多的细节，但那是另一个
level of study that is helpful in this
研究的水平是有所帮助
quest for knowing the truth and
寻求了解真相和
understanding the word well the second
第二个理解这个词
thing that we are to know according to
我们是一点根据知道
the Scriptures is to know God in a basic
圣经是基本认识上帝的
and practical way how can we as
和实际的方式我们怎么样
Christians really know God well we can
基督徒真的知道上帝以及我们可以
know about God the Father and God the
了解父神和神
Son accurately by studying everything
儿子通过研究一切准确
revealed about them in the Bible and
在圣经中透露了他们，
then we can also study in more detail
那么我们也可以更详细地研究
through these systematic theologies
通过这些系统的神学
systematic theologies include topical
系统神学包括主题
studies of everything in the Bible if
研究圣经中的一切如果
systematic theologies are new to you I
系统神学对你来说是新的我
encourage you to explore this type of
鼓励你探索这种类型的
study by studying theology proper the
通过研究神学来研究
theology of God the Father everything
父神的一切神学
the Bible says about God the Father and
圣经说的是父神和神
Christology everything the Bible says
基督论圣经所说的一切
about God the Son we come to a more
关于儿子，我们来了更多
thorough and comprehensive understanding
全面而全面的了解
of how the scriptures address the way we
经文如何解决我们的方式
can know God in a more deep and detailed
能够更深刻，更细致地认识上帝
understanding of each one well you see a
了解每一个，你看到了
long list there which systematic
那个系统的长列表
theologies might be most helpful for you
神学可能对你最有帮助
my encouragement is to talk to talk to a
我的鼓励是商量来商量到
leader at your church and just discuss
你教会的领导， 只是讨论
it with them they'll probably be able to
它与他们，他们可能会 能够
consider which type of study might be
考虑可能是哪种类型的研究
best for you they're all systematic
对你最好， 他们都是系统的
theologies they're all doing the same
他们都在做同样的神学
thing some are much more extensive in
事情有些是更广泛
how they treat each topic some are more
他们如何对待每个主题有些更多
concise there are also some that are a
简洁也有一些是
Baptist theology there are some that are
浸信会神学有一些是
a dispensational theology there are some
一个时代神学有一些
that are a reformed theology whichever
这是一个改革的神学，无论哪个
is your view studying studying the
是你研究学习的观点
systematic theology and all three can be
系统神学和三者都可以
beneficial but maybe a good starting
有益但可能是一个好的开始
point would be something that your
点是什么，你的
pastor or elder would recommend to you
牧师或长者会向你推荐
these are these are great studies and
这些都是伟大的研究和
this is a great method of study for us
这对我们来说是一种很好的学习方法
as Christians and as biblical counselors
作为基督徒和圣经辅导员
what do you get from this type of study
你从这种类型的研究中得到了什么？
of the word of looking through
通过找字
systematic theologies or doing original
系统神学或做原创
language studies you get a more detailed
语言学习你会得到更详细的
and accurate understanding of the word
并准确理解这个词
by looking through a summary of
通过汇总期待
everything the Bible says on a
圣经所说的一切
particular topic you have a framework so
你有一个特定主题的框架
that then as you read through the New
然后当你阅读新的
Testament over and over familiar
遗嘱一遍又一遍熟悉
passages that happen to talk about that
恰好谈论这段话的段落
topic and say something that's part of
主题并说出一些内容
that big picture of it now you see in
现在你看到它的大局
the perspective of everything the Bible
一切圣经的视角
says about it and with that framework
说这件事，并与框架
you understand verses more accurately
你更准确地理解经文
what really is being said there and
真正正在那里说和
phrases more accurately and even words
短语更准确， 甚至是单词
more accurately that's helpful because
更准确地说这是有用的，因为
the more we can know the word the more
我们越了解这个词就越多
accurately we can understand what the
准确地说我们可以理解什么了
scriptures say about the father and the
圣经说的父亲和
son that will strengthen us in our walk
儿子，这将加强我们的行走
with God and it'll help us to more
与上帝同在，它会帮助我们更多
accurately communicate the truth of the
准确地传达了真相
word to the people that we're counseling
告诉人们我们正在辅导
or disciple
或门徒
well what if you already have that what
好吧，如果你已经有了什么
if a significant knowledge of Scripture
如果有重要的圣经知识
and theology is already yours I
和神学已经是你我
encourage you with three things worship
鼓励你崇拜三件事
the Lord in humility those kind of
主谦卑那种
studies give us great opportunity for
研究给了我们很好的机会
worship also be strong in systematically
崇拜也有系统地强烈
replacing sin with righteousness by
用正义取代罪
God's efficient grace and His Word
上帝有效的恩典和他的话语
you were equipped to do that well and I
你有能力做到这一点，我
encourage you study carefully to
鼓励你仔细研究
continue to grow in the knowledge of God
继续在上帝的知识中成长
and His Word the more years go by
和他的话语越多年过去了
probably most of you who are a little
可能大多数人都是一点点
older like me can relate to this but if
像我这样 年长的人 可以与此相关但是如果
you've been a Christian for a while and
你已经是基督徒了一会儿 ，
you work hard at studying the word isn't
你努力学习这个词不是
one of the things you realize the depth
你意识到深度的事情之一
of the word the more you study the more
这个词越多你学习的越多
different ways you study God's Word the
不同的方式你研究上帝的话语
more you realize if we live to be a
更多的你意识到，如果我们活着成为一个
thousand years old
千岁
we wouldn't ever come close to getting
我们不会接近得到
to the full knowledge to the depth of
充分了解到深度
all of it and so God's grace you have a
所有这一切， 所以上帝的恩典，你有一个
number of years left on earth and you
地球上剩下的年数和你
already have a a good understanding of
已经有一个很好的 理解
the word and of theology keep going with
这个词和神学一直在继续
it
它
you have great years ahead what if you
如果你有好的表现，那么你还有很多年
don't what if this is some of these
如果这些是其中的一部分，请不要这样做
types of study are new ideas I encourage
研究类型是我鼓励的新想法
you read and apply the word daily having
你阅读并应用每日一词
that daily time to interact with the
每天与... 互动的时间
Almighty God is really essential for us
全能的上帝对我们来说真的很重要
to grow in Christ and to be best
在基督里成长，成为最好的
equipped for ministry to others
为他人服务
point number two there use good
点数二那里用得好
resources and other formats of study
资源和其他形式的研究
that are recommended by your elders or
这是你的长辈或
small group leaders or develop a way to
小组领导或开发方式
read and apply the word that best fits
阅读并应用最适合的词
you these are these are great studies
你这些都是伟大的研究
and this is a great method of study for
这是一个很好的学习方法
us as Christians and as bill
我们作为基督徒和法案
local councillors what do you get from
当地议员你从中获得了什么
this type of study of the word of
这种类型的字的研究
looking through systematic theologies
透过系统神学来看
are doing original language studies you
正在做原创语言研究
get a more detailed and accurate
得到更详细和准确
understanding of the word by looking
通过观察来理解这个词
through a summary of everything the
通过一切摘要
Bible says on a particular topic you
圣经说你特定的话题
have a framework so that then as you
有一个框架，那么就像你一样
read through the New Testament over and
通读和阅读新约圣经
over familiar passages that happen to
过去熟悉的段落
talk about that topic and say something
谈论这个话题并说些什么
that's part of that big picture of it
这是它那大图片的一部分
now you see in the perspective of
现在你看到的是
everything the Bible says about it and
一切圣经上说这件事和
with that framework you understand
你明白这个框架
verses more accurately what really is
更确切地说，究竟是什么
being said there and phrases more
在那里说和短语更多
accurately and even words more
准确甚至更多的话
accurately that's helpful because the
准确地说这是有用的，因为
more we can know the word the more
我们可以更多地了解这个词
accurately we can understand what the
准确地说我们可以理解什么了
scriptures say about the father and the
圣经说的父亲和
son that will strengthen us in our walk
儿子，这将加强我们的行走
with God and it'll help us to more
与上帝同在，它会帮助我们更多
accurately communicate the truth of the
准确地传达了真相
word to the people that were counseling
对那些提供咨询的人说
or disciple well what if you already
或者你的弟子，如果你已经
have that what if a significant
如果有意义的话，那就有了
knowledge of Scripture and theology is
圣经和神学的知识是
already yours I encourage you with three
已经是你了我鼓励你三个
things worship the Lord in humility
事物谦卑地崇拜主
those kind of studies give us great
那些研究给了我们很大的帮助
opportunity for worship also be strong
敬拜的机会也很强烈
in systematically replacing sin with
系统地用罪取代罪
righteousness by God's efficient grace
上帝的有效恩典是正义的
and his word you were equipped to do
和他的话你有能力去做
that well and I encourage you and then
那很好，我鼓励你，然后
also the word exposes the desires of the
也字暴露的欲望
heart this action of God creates daily
上帝的这一行动每天创造
the opportunity to become more like
机会变得更像
Christ
基督
I remember one time
我记得有一次
a friend talking about his father who
一个朋友在谈论他的父亲
was a strong Christian when he was near
当他在附近时，他是一个坚强的基督徒
death he had it was in the late stages
他有的死亡是在后期
of cancer he when he wasn't laying in
当他没有进入时，他会患上癌症
bed he was laying on the couch and he'd
他躺在沙发上睡觉了
be kind of in and out of awake or sleep
有点进出清醒或睡觉
and my friend asked him dad what's
我的朋友问他爸爸是什么
what's that like what's what's going on
什么是正在发生的事情
and the dad said honestly some of the
和父亲老老实实说了一些
greatest times I've ever had with the
我曾经有过的最伟大的时光
Lord he he'd think about passages that
主啊，他会想到那段经文
he had memorized and he'd review those
他已经记住了，他会审查这些
and he'd consider those with the Lord
他会考虑与主的关系
and God did what he always did he caused
上帝做了他所做的一切
the word to be living in active and and
这个词要活跃在和
this man who was in great pain and near
这个人非常痛苦，近在咫尺
death was communicating to his son how
死亡正在与他的儿子沟通如何
he was understanding new applications
他正在了解新的申请
and new truths from these passages in
从这些通道 和新的真理
this wonderful interaction that was
这个奇妙的互动，这是
going on between him and the Lord as he
在他和他之间继续前行
was near that lets be people who every
在附近，让每个人都成为
day at every station in life have that
生活中每个站点的那 一天 都有
interaction with God going on through
与上帝的互动 正在进行中
his word
他的话
and then growth in sanctification on our
然后在我们的成就上成长
own level helps us to better emphasize
自己的水平有助于我们更好地强调
understand and counsel others if we
如果我们理解并劝告他人
always have the particular sins that
总是有特定的罪过
we're trying to replace with
我们正试图替换
righteousness and the ones that last
正义和持久的
year by God's grace were replaced with
上帝的恩典被一年的恩典所取代
righteousness through the word if we're
如果我们是正义的话
always in the battle to become more like
总是在战斗中变得更像
Christ we'll be able to best empathize
基督，我们将能够最好地同情
with those people that we're serving
与那些我们服务的人
understand them and counsel them
了解他们并为他们提供建议
accurately from God's Word the book of
准确地从神的话语中得到了这本书
Proverbs
箴言
contrasts the wise person with the
对比明智的人与
foolish person and our third
愚蠢的人和我们的第三个人
qualification for the biblical counselor
圣经辅导员的资格
is wisdom Colossians 3:16 says that we
是智慧歌罗西书3:16说我们
are to admonish or Noosa teto one
是劝告或Noosateto one
another in wisdom so let's take a look
智慧中的另一个让我们来看看
at wisdom in the book of Proverbs in
在箴言书中的智慧
Proverbs we have a contrast the wise
谚语我们有明智的对比
person and the foolish person the wise
聪明的人和愚蠢的人
person who has a right understanding of
有正确理解的人
God and lives accordingly and the
上帝和相应的生活和
foolish person who lives for selfish
为自私而活着的愚蠢人
purposes as if God doesn't even exist
目的好像上帝甚至不存在
let's think through these the wise
让我们通过这些明智的思考
person acts and thinks and says his or
人行为，思考，说他或他
her desires on bringing glory and honor
她带来荣耀和荣誉的欲望
to God proverbs 13:20 he who walks with
上帝箴言13:20与他同行的人
wise men will be wise but the companion
聪明人将是聪明的，但同伴
of fools will suffer harm proverbs 15 28
傻瓜会受到伤害谚语15 28
the heart of the wise Ponder's how to
明智的思考的核心是如何
answer but the mouth of the wicked pours
回答但是恶人的嘴巴倒了
out evil things proverbs 15 31 he whose
邪恶的事情谚语15 31他的
ear listens to life-giving reproof will
耳朵倾听生命的责备意志
dwell among the wise proverbs 17:17 a
住在智慧箴言中17:17 a
friend loves at all times and a brother
朋友总是喜欢和兄弟一起爱
is born
出生了
adversity so here we see some examples
逆境所以我们在这里看到一些例子
of how the wise person thinks what they
聪明人如何看待他们
want and what they do we need this kind
想要和他们做什么我们需要这种
of wisdom if these things are the
如果这些东西是智慧的
pattern of who we are and what we do
我们是谁以及我们做什么的模式
because we are striving to be wise we
因为我们正努力做到明智
are striving to live our lives in a way
正在努力以某种方式过我们的生活
that honors God then we will think
尊重上帝然后我们会思考
before we speak and when we're approved
在我们发言之前和我们获得批准之前
we'll listen and we'll be that friend
我们会听，我们会成为那个朋友
who is the best friend to our the people
谁是我们人民最好的朋友
God brings across our path in their
上帝带来了我们的道路
times of adversity this is wisdom let's
逆境的时候，这就是智慧
contrast that with the foolish the
与愚蠢的对比
foolish person is selfish and behaving
愚蠢的人是自私和行为
as if God doesn't even exist consider
仿佛上帝甚至不存在考虑
these examples lying lips are an
这些例子说谎嘴唇是一个
abomination to the Lord but those who
憎恶耶和华，但那些人
deal faithfully are his delight if there
处理忠实地为他所喜悦，如果有
is no God if God isn't watching what I'm
如果上帝不看我的样子，那就不是上帝
doing if he isn't judging the thoughts
如果他不判断这些想法就会这样做
and intentions of my heart well lying
心里的意图很好说谎
would probably make sense gee it'll save
可能会有意义，它会节省
me a lot of trouble if I just tell
如果我告诉我，我会遇到很多麻烦
people that something else really
人们真的有别的东西
happened but if I'm thinking in terms of
发生了，但如果我在考虑
the true God and my purpose really is to
真正的上帝和我的目的确实是
honor him the lying would make no sense
尊敬他说谎是没有意义的
proverbs 13 for the soul of the sluggard
谚语13为懒惰 的灵魂
craves and gets nothing but the soul of
渴望并得到灵魂
the diligent is made fat there again we
勤奋又在那里发胖我们
have the contrast of the wise and the
有智慧和对比的对比
foolish to the foolish it doesn't make
愚蠢到它没有做到的愚蠢
sense to work hard what's in it for me
感觉要为我努力工作
proverbs 16 5 everyone who is proud in
谚语16 5每个自豪的人
heart is an abomination to the Lord
心是耶和华所憎恶的
assuredly he will not go unpunished
他肯定不会逍遥法外
we live in a culture where pride is said
我们生活在一个文化，骄傲的说
to be good but it's not it's foolishness
要好，但这不是愚蠢
because it puts itself in the place of
因为它使自己置身于...
God in proverbs 23 verses 4 & 5 do not
神在箴言23节4＆5不
worry yourself to gain wealth when you
担心你自己获得财富
set your eyes on it it is gone similarly
设置你的眼睛上它，它也同样消失了
if we are living for a year and now
如果我们生活一年，现在
we're always thinking about more money
我们一直在考虑更多的钱
more stuff more things we can buy with
我们可以购买更多东西
money that isn't the wisdom of seeking
金钱不是寻求的智慧
to honor God in every part of life well
在生活的每一个方面都要尊荣上帝
God teaches us what to want and how to
上帝教导我们想要什么以及如何做
think and act to obtain wisdom we as
思考并采取行动以获得我们的智慧
biblical counselors and disciple errs
圣经辅导员和门徒
must have this quest for wisdom
必须有这种对智慧的追求
look at how proverbs begins to know
看看谚语是如何开始认识的
wisdom and instruction to discern the
智慧和指令辨别
sayings of understanding to receive
接受理解的说法
instruction and wise behavior a wise man
指导和明智的行为是一个聪明人
will hear and increase in learning the
会听到并增加学习的
fear of the Lord is the beginning of
敬畏耶和华是开始的
knowledge fools despise wisdom and
知识傻瓜鄙视智慧和
instruction so we are seeking wisdom and
指导所以我们正在寻求智慧和
understanding we are interacting with
了解我们正在与之互动
God daily so that we can have more of it
每天上帝让我们可以拥有更多
and the beginning of it is the fear of
而它的开始是对...的恐惧
the Lord we're we're doing all this
主啊，我们正在做这一切
we're expending energy and time in this
我们在这方面耗费精力和时间
quest for wisdom because we love God and
寻求智慧，因为我们爱上帝和
we want to honor him proverbs 4 verses 5
我们要尊重他的箴言4节5节
through 8 the Father speaking to the son
通过8 父说话的儿子
acquire wisdom acquire understanding do
获得智慧获得理解
not forsake her and she will guard you
不要丢弃她，她会保护你
love her and she will watch over you the
爱她， 她就保守你的
beginning of wisdom is this acquire
智慧的开始是这种获得
wisdom and with your acquiring get
智慧和你的获得得到
understanding prize her and
理解奖励她和
you will exalt you let us be diligent in
你要尊崇你让我们在勤奋
our quest for this wisdom for the
我们追求这种智慧
biblical counselor
圣经辅导员
wisdom is the ability to answer the
智慧是回答的能力
question well what does the Bible say
问问圣经说的是什么
about that every case presents multiple
关于每个案例都呈现多重
opportunities to answer that question
机会来回答这个问题
for the biblical counselor what do we do
对于圣经辅导员我们做了什么
in those times if we know the answer to
在那些时候， 如果我们知道答案
the question from God's Word if we know
如果我们知道的话，来自神的话语的问题
how the word applies to that we say what
这个词怎么适用于我们说什么
it is and we say it with compassion and
它是，我们用同情心来说
with the authority that God's Word
有上帝之道的权威
demands if we don't we say to the person
要求我们不要对这个人说
that we're serving I'm not sure exactly
我们正在服务，我不确定
what the Bible says about that but I'm
圣经对此有何评价，但我是
gonna spend this week studying and with
要去 这一周的时间学习，并与
the Lord figuring it out and I'll let
主把它弄清楚，我会放过
you know next week when we're
你知道下周我们的时候
communicating wisdom from the word the
从这个词传达智慧
truth of the word what the Bible does
这个词的真相是圣经的作用
say about that the motive the actions
说出行动的动机
the thoughts of the counsel II then the
然后是律师II的想法
counsel he chooses a response either
律师他也选择了回应
they they choose to want and think and
他们选择想要和思考
do according to the scripture or they
根据经文或他们做
choose to be foolish according to
根据，选择愚蠢
proverbs they choose to rather live for
他们选择宁愿生活的谚语
self and live for the moment and live in
自我，活在当下，生活在
a way that acts as if God and his word
一种充当上帝和他的话语的方式
don't even exist this is the drama in
甚至不存在，这是中戏
the counseling room those are big
咨询室那些很大
choices it matters a lot to God and if
选择对上帝来说很重要，如果
you care about this person it matters a
你关心这个人很重要
lot to you which they choose well what
很多你，他们选择什么好
if you have this wisdom what if this is
如果你有这种智慧，如果是这样的话
something you have quite a bit of
你拥有的东西相当多的
already here are my encouragement tested
已经在这里受到我的鼓励测试
by scripture use it to gather data and
通过经文使用它来收集数据和
communicate scripture wealth and sharpen
传达经文财富和锐化
it by the daily spiritual disciplines
它是由日常的精神学科
and by God's Word
并借着上帝的话语
what if we don't have enough of it what
如果我们没有足够的东西怎么办？
if it just takes more time to figure out
如果它只是需要更多的时间来弄清楚
how the word applies to specific
这个词如何适用于具体的
situations proverbs is so helpful that
情况谚语是非常实用，
that verse-by-verse contrast of the
这节经文的对比
foolish way of thinking how the person
愚蠢的思考方式是怎样的人
thinks if they think there is no God or
认为如果他们认为没有上帝或者
if they act as if there is no God versus
如果他们表现得好像没有上帝对抗
how the wise person thinks the person
聪明人如何看待这个人
who is seeking to bring glory and honor
谁想要带来荣耀和荣誉
to God that comparison over and over and
向上帝反复比较和
over in 31 chapters will help us grow in
超过31章将帮助我们成长
wisdom we also grow in wisdom through
智慧我们也通过智慧成长
the topical study of Scripture and the
圣经和局部的研究
good theology resources discussed
讨论了很好的神学资源
earlier it's just important for all of
早些时候它对所有人来说都很重要
us to do the hard work of systematic
我们要做好系统的努力
study of the Bible's truth if we do that
如果我们这样做，就要研究圣经的真理
we'll be able to best apply the word to
我们将能够最好地应用这个词
our own lives and in the lives of the
我们自己的生活和生活中的生活
people God brings across our path how
上帝带来了我们的道路如何
does this benefit our ministry those who
这对我们的事工有益吗？
by practice have developed a stronger
通过实践发展得更强
ability to discern how the scriptures
能够辨别经文的方式
address motives and life issues will be
解决动机和生活问题
more effective in counseling other
更有效地辅导其他
people from the word well our study
从我们的研究中得到的人
wouldn't be complete without the
没有这个就不会完整
presentation of some other pertinent
介绍其他一些相关的
studies they are printed for you in your
研究它们是为你打印的
syllabus the first one is a study of
大纲第一个是的研究
first Timothy 3:1 the second is a
第一个提摩太前书3：1，第二个是
reference to chapter 7 of the book
参考本书第7章
counseling how to counsel biblically by
咨询如何以圣经的方式提供咨询
John MacArthur that chapter was written
约翰麦克阿瑟这一章写的
by dr. Robert Smith a medical doctor and
由博士。罗伯特史密斯医生和
Naing board member and he's talking
Naing董事会成员，他在说话
about these basic things the the
关于这些基本的东西了
personal disciplines that are necessary
个人纪律是必要的
for the biblical counselor good reading
对于圣经辅导员的良好阅读
and number three is a book by Don
唐三是唐书
Whitney we have some of those here it's
惠特尼， 我们有一些人在这里
called spiritual dis
所谓精神DIS
one's for the Christian life he explores
他探索的基督徒生活的一个
in detail the spiritual disciplines that
详细的精神学科
will benefit us in knowing and putting
知道和投入会使我们受益
into practice God's Word so goodness
实践上帝的话语如此善良
knowledge and wisdom may we each be
我们每个人都可以拥有知识和智慧
growing in these and may it be a great
在这些中成长，可能是一个伟大的
adventure between each of us and the
我们每个人之间的冒险
Lord as we pursue these things and then
主，因为我们追求这些事情然后
may God be glorified in the interaction
愿上帝在互动中得到荣耀
that we have with other people as we put
我们和其他人一样
these things into practice in ministry
这些事情在事工中付诸实践
you
您